it has been a morning an amazing morning
and an amazing week I only decided to do
this yesterday and things happen between
now and then that I don't I'm going to
get into them right now because I want
to do this at the beginning so I am
crating we are going to create but right
now it's just me a global technical
cooperative because technology companies
have so much power right now they are
the top like four or five companies on
the stock exchange and they're growing
all the time between Amazon Apple
Facebook and I forgot one of them they
have more and more of our data more and
more money to affect our elections
oh hello Tiffany this is one of the
things I was doing today and I was going
to be talking to Tiffany and something
else came up which I will talk to you
about later so I have known I've had
this idea for a long time and it keeps
improving as time goes on but also I
really want to get it out there now and
what I keep trying to do I tried to
create a website I tried to have a blog
I tried to write a book and it doesn't
work
partly because like a business plan once
it's out there it's already updated it's
already evolving and the ideas we're
creating it together from scratch anyway
we're gonna create the way to fund it
the way to govern how we actually like
have a board of directors that we can
trust and can be run with with all of us
and so today because I have been very
versed on coming live and happy nobody
coming to ask questions I am going to
I've notes actually events I also don't
always have entitled right now
everything you can have with a check
with a tech cooperative and so people
don't always like it right but what's in
it for me or what's in it for the people
like that's great but why would people
want to get involved and for every
reason every reason that you currently
use technology that has a downside and a
plus side we can have the plus side with
very minimal downside when we own it
together when we
together and we can exponentially
increase the positive side that Google
Apple Facebook can't do because if
there's this disconnection between the
creator and the user and they have to
keep things behind a closed door and
they have to keep things the opposite of
transparent secret if keep things secret
in order to be have proprietary
information we don't need to do that
because we're going to be opening out in
the open for everyone to see so that
everybody can join oh thanks for sharing
Tiffany and so I just have a list of
like everything we can to be like
technological cooperative they just like
fall asleep above the tech and the
cooperative so here's there's a few
things we can create with technology
that already been created with
technology we just don't own them and
then other ones that have never been
created that we can create together I'm
not gonna distinguish between the two
but I have what you get when you have we
have a tech cooperative is access to
understandable usable information that
you can trust in basically all
information right now is on the internet
but each one of us has to decide whether
something is trustworthy or not and
there's definitely more trustworthy
sites than other ones but to some degree
that doesn't even matter because if
you're having a conversation with
someone and you don't have a foundation
that you can go back to you're gonna
have to have the same debate the same
conversation over and over again there
is way too much information on this
planet for any one person to hold it and
even if you were a phenomenal human
being could hold it in your brain the
person you're talking to can't and so
having one place right now I'd say the
closest thing to that is Wikipedia but
it's not necessarily we don't own it
together it's not as trustworthy because
someone coca-cola can come in and change
their their Wikipedia page so when we're
able to say what we trust and what we
don't trust together and as things go
wrong be like well look Coke is doing
their own their own thing we can problem
solve that and co-create ideas to
mitigate that without what Wikipedia
does which is lock-in understandable
information I don't find Wikipedia
exceptionally understandable
it's an encyclopedia online it's awesome
really glad it exists but it doesn't
work for neurologically diverse brain
it's not infographics it's not visual
it's not data we can play with having
people geeked out in their area of
choosing I understand the powers of and
this is what it's cool about this I hope
you don't want any but I can put up the
actual they comment on the screen so I
can read it we understand the powers of
tech outlet open source yeah
having science that we can trust
having science be a space of instead of
do you agree with it or not how solid is
the science how many people were
involved in the study who funded the
study having a space that we have
discussed before you don't get to say
whether or not this is this is a pro or
anti climate change someone who agrees
that are not agree with it we would have
algorithms that we decide on beforehand
if like this is how we grade science
having health that is that you can trust
that isn't necessarily a doctor who may
or may not be being paid by the
pharmaceutical company and may or may
not be trained within the box of the
medical community which is everyone is
in in their own box economics we all
spend money everywhere we go and yet the
system is getting more more complex
where that mine is going and my theme
war am i funding misery with this when I
buy this chocolate bar like what to be
able to have access to what economics is
actually doing including
following the resources following like
what actually went into this how much
water how much energy how much misery
went into what I am buying and then
backtracking and creating it ourselves
saying okay well I like chocolate I
would like a good chocolate bar that
doesn't creep and misery and I need it
not to me five dollars a bar how can we
create a world that works for everyone
works for the the cocoa farmers works
for me eating it works for the
transportation and we can create that
all with technology much more simply
than we can with it because that law so
you're gonna know what's in something
and be able to constantly constantly
update it as it improves and as
companies that are both for-profit and
our own
improve to instill values that we want
to support how do we then start to
support them more and more history is
something that is not black and white
but we need to have more opinions on it
I would love to have like sites about
interviewing your grandparents all the
time of and have it
metadata where you can link like this is
their thing of world war two this is how
they've got the love of their life if
this is even everyday stories from the
people who are alive currently who are
in their 80s and 90s and possibly even
our 100 is lost when they go away and we
need to be able to to archive that
information Willie Utley if the person's
willing and have it be tagged so we can
find it and have it be the history of
every culture and the history of the
world in a way I would love to zoom in
and out like a Google map or you can
zoom in all the way from Penn Geo when
all the continents were together to the
current day and you can see how ideas
have moved and how people have moved
what was going on at the time at the
time of Columbus what was going on at
the time of Darwin and who else was
alive at that time what was going on in
art what was going on in science make it
come alive in a way that even a
documentary can't because once it's done
it's outdated already like it already
you have to go and do the research I
want us to collectively do the research
for most of what can be on the internet
without um without having to reinvent
the wheel every time so we can get on
with creating solutions instead of
discussing what's true and what's not
true
there's absolutely gray area nuance but
that can even put it in it as well like
right there
science usually does not come down 100%
on one thing or another there is a gray
area there is these statistics for a
reason history current events to
understand so much is rapidly happening
on our planet to be able to understand
the current events of like what is
happening like what's actually happening
what's the thing that there is no gray
area on like there was a bomb did it go
off yes okay that at least we know who
did it maybe we don't
then there's evidence for who did this
evidence for who did that what happened
why it happened how it happened when it
happened and where it happened and what
do we before anything actually takes
place what do we know to be true there's
six different people who don't know each
other all on their cell phones recording
it we can be fairly certain it's what's
accurate accession when it's from a
whole bunch of different angles but we
don't get to decide for the events we
trust in that that is that is good
enough information and then not for the
ones that we don't we don't trust in
politics we need to be able to know what
our politicians are saying whether
they're holding there whether they're
saying they're elected on a platform are
they following through we can grade them
we can keep information on corporations
and politicians we're scared of them
keeping it on us ours is a lot harder
they have to do it secretly we can do
theirs out in the open for everyone to
see and everyone can compile it and
everyone can come together and create it
so they can't spin it and it can't be
that the Trump supporters are gonna
badmouth Obama and Obama supporters are
gonna badmouth Trump it's like no how do
you know how big an inaugural crowd is
how do you know whether or not a
hurricane can be new how do you know
whether or not like having the actual
information again understandable for all
different neurodiversity and learning
styles having it usable so that we can
get as into the information or a surface
level as we need to be and having it be
trustworthy where did it come from it's
not good nothing is gonna be 100%
trustworthy but how can we always be
improving that and how can what's the
best information that's out there and
how can we put it in that way and so we
are going to create the system that
allows people to geek out in their area
of choosing for the benefit of society
you love history make history come alive
for the rest of us who love science
makes science come alive for the rest of
us and so this is one point information
that we get access to that we don't
currently have access to we can do much
better together in a cooperative because
we can have the conversations about
whether we trust it or not one of the
other big things we can do is create
community create actual people there's a
lot of hope the word is which often
happens to me
um that like people don't care and
people are disconnected on social media
and I don't find that at all I find
people passionate and caring and
intelligent it's just not everyone has
every intelligent not everyone likes
everyone we just need to help people
find their people and so things that I
see us doing in this in this area are
things like creating a dating site that
we actually want to be on for the
diversity that exists in our sexuality
and gender and romantic selves all the
spectrums all of it in one place so that
there doesn't need to be 18 different
dating sites there's we're all
concentrated on one and yet it works in
a way that isn't shopping that everyone
seems to find superficial and annoying
um like dating sites for introverts
dating sites for like okay here are
questions you can ask so that it
actually rolls well it has like a
photographer come and and take a picture
of you like they used to do on Airbnb so
that you're shown in a good light
literally a good light an activity
coordinator which is meet up meet up
exists and but now it costs money to
create any kind of a group and plus it's
it's in the real world creating meetups
that are also online so if you have a
really niche interest and you're in a
small town you can still find people to
talk about it with in your area in your
language in your time zone like not area
sorry yeah like your area of interest
your time zones when you're available
and in the language way you communicate
having rich goes on to the next one
which is actually our first project our
first actual project of the technology
technology cooperative it's its own
YouTube channel now called idea cafe
which I will link in the comments after
this or in the description sorry where
when we create our own social media
platform are people to come to have an
actual conversation a conversation where
you don't need to bring the people the
questions already their humanity can
come and participate in it and I'm not
the one creating the question we can
submit questions we can make them better
and we can create different niches if
the all the people want to get to come
and talk about climate change here's the
question on climate change for that day
everyone's together together and talk
about poverty here's the question on
poverty and we will have one in each
area that is this that is the technology
cooperative
and even that's gonna happen some dishes
the financial department the legal
department the security department where
you want to geek out for the betterment
of society and the betterment of the
cooperative and nobody has to do any of
it like you don't you're not asked even
assigned a role you can get into other
things that aren't what the technology
is gonna give you so creating community
is also voting creating the platform
that helps people find what is easy and
enjoyable for them to contribute for
every task that needs to get done there
are people out there who would love to
do it are great at doing it and
therefore would do it for free
especially if it's not a full-time job
and it's something that could be done by
volunteer and there's some stuff that's
not gonna be done in that way and we're
gonna have to pay people to do it but
creating the platform to harness as much
free labor the people want to give
they're just looking for someone to give
it it's just not organized yet is one of
the ways we have immense advantage over
the for-profit tech companies and the
for-profit system that has to pay it it
has to we can epically pay less and so
why not well we also were creating the
world that goes into our next area which
is um resources we can give each other
access to food water energy clothing
shelter connection like all of the
things that make life worth living I
participate in a meal group three times
a week and recently I have been getting
fresh prep meals delivered because I got
in Tegel on them and there they all have
deals to sign up and creating something
like the fresh prep that mimics also the
community that I eat with is a way that
we can have people of all socioeconomic
status being able to eat healthy and
conveniently within their own means of
how much energy they have how much time
they have how much money they have by
coordinating our labor bike or bike
coordinated in our purchasing power and
that is a platform we can create
together we can create the online
farmers market it's a farmers don't have
to sit there and sell their goods for
eight hours which I get to add into the
cost and makes farmers market yes
fun fun to go to but not all accessible
to people who don't have money or the
means to get there or working full time
including the farmers themselves there
are ways that we can create shelter for
much much cheaper than we currently are
including how we have a political
movement within every city to make how
is he more affordable I live in one of
the most expensive housing markets in
the world Vancouver and like a
accessible financial of financially
accessible bachelor suite is supposed to
be like $2,200 no that's not accessible
we can create two libraries and
appliance libraries where we are sharing
in the the goods important I mean I just
needed a pair of rain boots yesterday
for my for my daughter because she had
Gruber last ones and I can go and buy a
cheap pair that you're gonna break in
three months for 20 bucks I can look for
a secondhand ones I can buy for 20 bucks
but I just reached a community asking
for a pair and I got them to coordinate
that so that no kid goes without ringing
gear no kid goes without wintry gear no
matter what your socio-economic Scottie
said whether it's because you want to be
kind to the earth or because you can't
afford it or because you just want other
people who can't afford I want to be
kind to the earth to have access to it
we can create the platforms that gives
us access to all of the stuff need and
the last one I have here which
definitely goes to community is
diversity true diversity we have 7.5
billion individuals on this planet and
that is our biggest strength we talk
about humans like we're a plague on this
planet and although up till this point
we kind of have been we also are 7.5
billion solutions every sing in every
single individual has their own unique
set of experiences that they've had like
their combination of experiences their
talents and their challenges and when we
pick big compass the perfect them and
when we're able to come together and
create the tools to harness that create
the tools to say okay well how do I find
other people with my same learning style
so when they learn some
I don't have to start from scratch I
know that if they learned it that way I
can probably learn it that way at the
same time no one's gonna be exactly like
me no one's gonna have my learning style
my taste palate my blood type my
genetics buy all of the stuff I am
unique and yet we're also not unique and
so to be able to give everyone what they
need in tech is available in technology
in a way it never was before we don't
need to dissipate the energy and
dissipate the the resources in a way
that we currently do on technology like
ok some of the you know the artists are
an Instagram and the the intellectuals
are on Twitter I don't know that's true
but like the whereas ok well what if my
people on Instagram right like what if
the people who helped critical the
co-operative I don't like Instagram
though and I don't know how to undertake
that it's gonna be dissipated but in
that same way like with a dating site if
we're all if like the farmers are on the
farmer dating site and and the
photographer is on the photographer
dating site but like right but I'm a
farmer in one day a photographer or I'm
open to dating a photographer the more
we dissipate things the more we're not
dismantling capitalism and creating a
world that works for everyone in a way
that is that is safe and peaceful and
enjoyable we can have fun doing this
because we're gonna create the tools to
constantly ask what's hard about this
how do we make it easier what's not fun
about this how do we make it enjoyable
how do we gamify it how do like if
you're spending time on a different
social media platform and the one that
we are creating together that's solving
the world's problems why why are you
there not don't you be there like what
is it they're giving you that we're not
how do we create that here - you're here
even if it's sharing photographs even if
it's like you can do exactly what you're
doing there let's do that here well
you're also creating a community around
saving our planet without if you don't
wanna concentrate on like the disaster
that our planet is those of us with the
emotional capacity and to do that
emotional labor be happy to do it and
that's the point is allowing people to
do what they're here to do and that is
my notes so that is what we can
by having a technology cooperative we
can create the tools for access to
information have everybody be able to
understand what is going on in the
complex issues because we have a fact we
don't have to reinvent the wheel every
time we have a we have a conversation we
don't need to have the climate debate
for the umpteenth time we need climate
information laid out so there basically
isn't a debate and the Koch brothers
can't skew that debate
brother we can have a community we can
connect people with who they are
everybody's worthy of connection
everyone should have people even if I
don't want to be your people and you
don't want to be my people that doesn't
mean you're not invited and that doesn't
mean you don't get a table to sit at
everyone is worthy and the more people
are connected people who are happy are
better human beings and I want people to
be better human beings so I want them
connected we can share resources
everyone again is worthy of food and
clothing and shelter and health and
education that is usable for them and we
can create those systems without needing
to petition our governments without
needing to like convince people who
don't want their taxpayers to go to that
to go to that let's voluntarily create
the thing that we've chosen to put our
money towards we get to honor her
diversity which again is about the
community we might not get along with
everybody
we might not we're not gonna get along
with everybody but creating in a way
where we can honor that if we have to
first get along on this planet before we
can create anything it's not gonna
happen so let's figure out how we create
a better world well we can also disagree
and also be on completely different
sides you can like want me dead and I
can still help you with a better life
just no actual violence and so today
there weren't a lot of questions I knew
that was going to be the case because
I'm talking to myself for a while now um
I am going to go since there are people
asking questions that this is going to
be weekly events I'm gonna come on I
will do a different topic next week it
might be what the governance structure
is what our board of directors is gonna
look like and anyone can come on and ask
any question about the technology
cooperative and how do we create a
better world together and I will answer
it because that's what my brain does
I'll be able to sit down and write this
in a book but it can answer questions
and focus that way especially when I can
look back at them and this how I end
them all on YouTube I'm three and daily
videos is a better world is on its way
and I've never felt that more strongly
than I do right now after what happened
today who I was connected with which I'm
now gonna be doing research on this new
this thing I just I literally I don't
even know what it is that's how new it
is called game B and being on this this
phone call this morning I launched the
idea cafe on September 11 and that had
so much meaning even though I did not
mean to it all and how it came together
was perfect and then I want him like
what I also really just want to talk
cooperative and so I created this space
to do what I want to do which is answer
questions on technology even though I am
not first in technology not actually
creating it I can't code I dislike slack
I dislike discord because they don't
work for my brain and yet I'm like and
I'm crazy the technology cooperative
it's gonna fix it all cuz I'm brain can
create this it can create a new way to
solve a problem with technology every
time there's a problem it's well we
hadn't after that and yet our eye can
see how our world our economic system
doesn't work to create apps not from
scratch not in the grassroots because
then you have to fight against the
system you have to fight against Google
and how you make it is by being bought
by them and then they have more power
and we have less and so we can come
together and create something that the
for-profit companies will never be able
to create we can do it out in the open
for everyone to see because that gives
us more power that gives us less
likelihood that they can come in and
wreck it when it's like right we have to
be open and transparent to our members
we're creating everything online for
everyone to see out in the open here's I
would love people who are comfortable
that to come on board if you want to be
part of the conversation that's going to
going to change Mandy and create the
platform for Humanity to come to for a
conversation you can join the idea cafe
Wednesdays at eleven a m-- pacific
standard time there's gonna be a new
question every week and we are going to
talk in an intimate setting as in a tiny
group of us but for everyone to see and
eventually that
platform will be created in a way where
people don't need to come on YouTube and
do it won't be using zoom in the
intermediate time so anyone who wants to
come on and talk to people on camera or
voice without the world's the unit that
will be accessible and then I'm doing
this the the crowd democracy explaining
the together tech project how we create
the Netflix of apps how we create the
thing that actually creates technology
that makes our lives better and how it
entered all weaves together to create a
world that works for everybody
and dismantles all of the corruption and
greed and crap that is currently boiling
our planet so please join me on fridays
at 11:00 or wednesdays at 11:00 on the
two different channels follow me on
twitter at democracy that our world is
on its way and it's gonna be brought to
you by our humanity's amazing diversity
take care and I will see you tomorrow